MUHAMAD RAASIKH FIL'ILMI



() 62 858 9510 8722

rafliiraasikh@gmail.com



https://portofolio-raasikh.vercel.app/

PROFESIONAL PROFILE

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/raasikhfililmi

I am Muhamad Raasikh Fil'ilmi. I am currently pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Informatics Engineering at Surabaya State University, currently in my 4th semester. I possess expertise in HTML, JavaScript, CSS, UI/UX, Python, and Laravel for web development, along with skills in public speaking, leadership, event management, and data analysis. I am a person who easily learns new things, communicative, and can do problem solving well. In accordance with my educational background, I have an interest in the fields of Web Developer, UI/UX Designer, Front-End Development, Backend Development, Business Development, Systems and Data Analyst.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

S1 TEKNIK INFORMATIKA / 3.81 | UNIVERSITAS NEGERI SURABAYA | 2022 - NOW

- Learn basic programming for C++, HTML, Javascript, Python, CSS, and SQL to apply the concept of the next programming in backend developing.
- Learn advanced programming namely object-oriented programming (OOP) to find out the content of the world programming.
- Learn human-computer interaction for UI/UX and react js for frontend developing.

SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL

ILMU PENGETAHUAN ALAM | SMA NEGERI 1 KRIAN | 2019 - 2022

- Studying the fundamentals of science and mathematics serves as a foundation for learning computational science and computer statistics.
- Studying computer science and data analysis, as well as coding in Python and HTML programming languages.
- Gaining initial understanding of fundamental concepts in software development, data structures, algorithms, and programming languages.

EXPERIENCE

EVENT DIVISION AND MASTER OF CEREMONY AT GOOGLE IOX 2024 BY GDG CLOUD	2024
FRONTEND DEV SCHOLAR INTERNSHIP AT AI4IMPACT 2.0	2022 - 2023
CONTRIBUTED TO RESEARCH PROJECTS LEAD BY LECTURER AS THE FRONTEND DEV	2023
PASSING INTERNAL FUNDING SELECTION FOR PKM (COMMUNITY SERVICE PROGRAM)	2022-2023
EVENT DIVISION AND MASTER OF CEREMONY AT DEVFEST 2023 BY GDG SURABAYA	2023
EVENT MANAGER AND MASTER OF CEREMONY AT THE MAC 5.0 EVENT IN EAST JAVA	2021

ACHIEVEMENT

- PASS FUNDING PROGRAM PENGUATAN KAPASITAS ORMAWA KEMENDIKBUD 2023
- PASS FUNDING FOR THE DELEGATION FOR THE AI4IMPACT 2.0 INTERNSHIP PROGRAM IN SINGAPORE.
- 2ND PLACE WINNER AT THE BASIC MEDICAL OLYMPIAD INDONESIA 2022 BY SMARTSTUDENT.ID

PROJECT

MOBILE APPLICATION UI/UX "REACH" 2024

User Interface and User Experience of the "REACH" Mobile Application focused on Food Sales, Digital Wallet, Waste Transactions, Road Monitoring, and Clean Water Monitoring in Sidoarjo.

Using: Figma and Canva.

GRAPHICAL USER INTERFACES "FITNESS TRACKER" 2024

Developing a graphical-based information system interface "Fitness Tracker" that operates in the health sector. This GUI performs heart health checks for the community and provides solutions to the problems found.

Using: Python.

WEBSITE FOR SONGGORITI VILLAGE "SONGGORITI.EP" 2024

Developed the "Songgoriti.EP" website for Songgoriti Village in 2024. The website providing residents and visitors with access to village news, events, services, and resources. Additionally, the website facilitates sales for local UMKM, offering a marketplace for villagers to sell their goods and services. *Using: React JS, Tailwind CSS, Laravel.*

REMAKING WEBSITE BEM UNESA FOR EDUCATION ON HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION 2023

Redesigning and recoding the BEM UNESA website 2023. Making it more user-friendly, fixing bugs, and enhancing its visual appeal.

Using: HTML, Tailwind CSS, Javascript.

WEBSITE COURSING HARDWARE & SOFTWARE "BLITZZ" 2023

Developed the "Blitzz" website, designed for beginner learning in the IT industry. The website includes courses on hardware and software, as well as integrated quizzes to reinforce learning.

Using: HTML and CSS.

GRAPHICAL USER INTERFACES "ERIFANTI RESTAURANT RESERVATION" 2023

Developing a graphical-based information system interface "Erifanti Restaurant Reservation" that operates in the food and beverage sector. This GUI implements algebraic algorithms for food ordering and table reservation at Erifanti Restaurant.

Using: Python.

MOBILE APPLICATION FOR POND WATER MONITORING "SEMONI" 2023

A mobile application for monitoring milkfish ponds in Semampir Village, Cerme District, Gresik Regency. The monitoring includes temperature, water salinity, water oxygen levels, and water pH. The application is also connected to an IoT aerator with sensors to stabilize pH and oxygen levels in the water.

Using: HTML, Tailwind CSS, Javascript, Figma, Canva, iOT using pythton.

GRAPHICAL USER INTERFACES "ANAFESA HOTEL RESERVATION" 2023

Developing a graphical-based information system interface "Anafesa" that operates in the service sector. This GUI implements room booking algorithms for Anafesa Hotel.

Using: Python.

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

VICE CHAIRMAN OF HMP TEKNIK INFORMATIKA UNESA (FEBRUARI 2024 - NOW)

- Leading nine departments within: the Student Resources Development Department, the
 Research and Technology Department, and the Talent and Interest Department, Ministry of
 Home Affairs, Ministry of Religious Affairs, Department of Entrepreneurship, Ministry of Foreign
 Affairs, Ministry of Communication and Informatics, Department of Project Events
- Responsible for the internal relations of the Computer Science Engineering department.

STAFF OF THE DEPARTMENT OF STUDENT RESOURCE DEVELOPMENT OF HIMTI (2023 - 2024)

- Participating in the community service activity "Informatics Big Camp" organized by the Informatics Engineering Student Association.
- Participating in the organization of the orientation event for new active members of the Computer Engineering department.
- Being the master of ceremony at the community service event in Begaganlimo Village,
 Mojokerto.

VICE CHAIRMAN OF MPK IN SMA NEGERI 1 KRIAN (2020 - 2021)

- Participating actively in community service activities, specifically in the voluntary work in Bibis Village.
- Led the internal student council in executing and overseeing school programs.
- Established regulations for all extracurricular activities at the school every mid-quarter.

SKILLS				
WEB DEVELOPER	TAILWIND	DATA ANALYST	FRONTEND	UI/UX
TEAMWORK	FLUENT IN ENGLISH	PUBLIC SPEAKING	CRITICAL THINKING	LEADERSHIP